[
  {
    "id": 3101,
    "question": "gastar",
    "questionDetails": "Y no habrá muchas ocasiones de gastar.",
    "answer": "spend",
    "answerDetails": "And it will not have many occasions to spend."
  },
  {
    "id": 3102,
    "question": "quitarme",
    "questionDetails": "Y quitarme mis cosas y luego.",
    "answer": "take",
    "answerDetails": "And take my things from me and then."
  },
  {
    "id": 3103,
    "question": "firmado",
    "questionDetails": "Este es un formulario de consentimiento firmado.",
    "answer": "signed",
    "answerDetails": "This is a signed consent form."
  },
  {
    "id": 3104,
    "question": "perdemos",
    "questionDetails": "Ganamos o perdemos juntos.",
    "answer": "lose",
    "answerDetails": "We gain or lose together."
  },
  {
    "id": 3105,
    "question": "encontraba",
    "questionDetails": "Encontraba toda clase de razones y excusas.",
    "answer": "found",
    "answerDetails": "I found all kinds of reasons and excuses."
  },
  {
    "id": 3106,
    "question": "serlo",
    "questionDetails": "Muy severa, tiene que serlo.",
    "answer": "be",
    "answerDetails": "It has to be."
  },
  {
    "id": 3107,
    "question": "situaciones",
    "questionDetails": "Trabaja bien en situaciones de grupo.",
    "answer": "situations, scenarios",
    "answerDetails": "Works well in group situations."
  },
  {
    "id": 3108,
    "question": "leído",
    "questionDetails": "He leído que va más rápido si caminas.",
    "answer": "read",
    "answerDetails": "I read it goes faster if you walk around."
  },
  {
    "id": 3109,
    "question": "continúa",
    "questionDetails": "Y el ciclo continúa.",
    "answer": "continues, remains",
    "answerDetails": "And on the cycle continues."
  },
  {
    "id": 3110,
    "question": "preguntan",
    "questionDetails": "Los campesinos preguntan por la oración de la lluvia.",
    "answer": "ask, wonder",
    "answerDetails": "Peasants ask about the rain prayer."
  },
  {
    "id": 3111,
    "question": "güey",
    "questionDetails": "Ese es el problema del cerebro, güey.",
    "answer": "dude",
    "answerDetails": "That is the problem with the brain, dude."
  },
  {
    "id": 3112,
    "question": "mirá",
    "questionDetails": "Y mirá lo que pasó.",
    "answer": "look",
    "answerDetails": "And look what happened."
  },
  {
    "id": 3113,
    "question": "jorge",
    "answer": "Jorge"
  },
  {
    "id": 3114,
    "question": "bye",
    "questionDetails": "… en el próximo video, bye!",
    "answer": "bye",
    "answerDetails": "… in the next video, bye!"
  },
  {
    "id": 3115,
    "question": "julio",
    "answer": "July"
  },
  {
    "id": 3116,
    "question": "entendió",
    "questionDetails": "Le mostré la canción a Federico, y entendió la letra porque habla español.",
    "answer": "he understood, he saw, she knew",
    "answerDetails": "I played the song for Federico, and he understood the lyrics because he speaks Spanish."
  },
  {
    "id": 3117,
    "question": "entienda",
    "questionDetails": "Espero que lo entienda.",
    "answer": "understand",
    "answerDetails": "I think you can understand that."
  },
  {
    "id": 3118,
    "question": "imagina",
    "questionDetails": "Imagina el conocimiento que está esperando.",
    "answer": "imagine, pretend, suppose",
    "answerDetails": "Imagine the knowledge that waits."
  },
  {
    "id": 3119,
    "question": "estáis",
    "questionDetails": "Así que estáis viviendo aquí.",
    "answer": "are, ye",
    "answerDetails": "So you are living here."
  },
  {
    "id": 3120,
    "question": "colaborar",
    "questionDetails": "Durante la última guerra colaboraron con los nazis.",
    "answer": "collaborate",
    "answerDetails": "During the last war they collaborated with the Nazis."
  },
  {
    "id": 3121,
    "question": "kilos",
    "questionDetails": "Ciento trece kilos con cincuenta gramos.",
    "answer": "kilos, pounds, extra pounds",
    "answerDetails": "A hundred and thirteen kilos and fifty grams."
  },
  {
    "id": 3122,
    "question": "decente",
    "questionDetails": "Un vestido de cuello alto decente.",
    "answer": "decent",
    "answerDetails": "A decent high-necked dress."
  },
  {
    "id": 3123,
    "question": "logró",
    "questionDetails": "El ideal de la medicina preventiva se logró.",
    "answer": "attained, managed, accomplished",
    "answerDetails": "The ideal of preventive medicine was attained."
  },
  {
    "id": 3124,
    "question": "territorio",
    "questionDetails": "Viene con el territorio.",
    "answer": "territory",
    "answerDetails": "Comes with the territory."
  },
  {
    "id": 3125,
    "question": "cometer",
    "questionDetails": "O cuando se puede cometer el acto.",
    "answer": "commit",
    "answerDetails": "Or when they may commit the act."
  },
  {
    "id": 3126,
    "question": "contratar",
    "questionDetails": "Los Reyes obtuvieron dispensaciones para permitirles contratar partidos políticamente ventajosos.",
    "answer": "contract, employ",
    "answerDetails": "Kings obtained dispensations to enable them to contract politically advantageous matches."
  },
  {
    "id": 3127,
    "question": "amén",
    "questionDetails": "En el nombre de nuestro Sr. Jesucristo. Amén.",
    "answer": "amen",
    "answerDetails": "In the name of our Lord, Jesus Christ. Amen."
  },
  {
    "id": 3128,
    "question": "injusto",
    "questionDetails": "En momentos como estos el sistema legal parece inhumano e injusto.",
    "answer": "unfair",
    "answerDetails": "At times like these the legal system appears inhuman and unfair."
  },
  {
    "id": 3129,
    "question": "ayudarlo",
    "questionDetails": "Mi hijo tiene problemas, pero no sé cómo ayudarlo.",
    "answer": "help him",
    "answerDetails": "My son has problems, but I don’t know how to help him."
  },
  {
    "id": 3130,
    "question": "recomiendo",
    "answer": "Recommend"
  },
  {
    "id": 3131,
    "question": "lección",
    "questionDetails": "Entonces aprendiste una valiosa lección.",
    "answer": "lesson",
    "answerDetails": "So then you’ve learned a valuable moral lesson."
  },
  {
    "id": 3132,
    "question": "pensabas",
    "questionDetails": "Antes en el campamento de verano, nunca pensabas.",
    "answer": "thought",
    "answerDetails": "Back in summer camp, you never thought."
  },
  {
    "id": 3133,
    "question": "pedirme",
    "questionDetails": "Puedes pedirme cualquier cosa que necesites.",
    "answer": "ask me",
    "answerDetails": "You can ask me for anything you need."
  },
  {
    "id": 3134,
    "question": "salgamos",
    "questionDetails": "Todo volverá a comenzar una vez que salgamos de ésta.",
    "answer": "out",
    "answerDetails": "Everything starts over once we make it out of this."
  },
  {
    "id": 3135,
    "question": "ocultar",
    "questionDetails": "Estaban en gran esfuerzo para ocultar esa información del público.",
    "answer": "conceal",
    "answerDetails": "They were at great pains to conceal that information from the public."
  },
  {
    "id": 3136,
    "question": "madrugada",
    "questionDetails": "Estudiamos hasta las 5 de la madrugada.",
    "answer": "morning, dawn",
    "answerDetails": "We were studying till five in the morning."
  },
  {
    "id": 3137,
    "question": "llegara",
    "questionDetails": "Al poco de que él llegara.",
    "answer": "arrived, came",
    "answerDetails": "Soon after he arrived."
  },
  {
    "id": 3138,
    "question": "fuente",
    "questionDetails": "Este problema es la fuente de todos mis frustraciones.",
    "answer": "source, supply, font",
    "answerDetails": "This problem is the source of all my frustrations."
  },
  {
    "id": 3139,
    "question": "humilde",
    "questionDetails": "En mi humilde opinión.",
    "answer": "humble, lowly",
    "answerDetails": "In my humble opinion."
  },
  {
    "id": 3140,
    "question": "dándole",
    "questionDetails": "Dándole a las cosas un aire de final.",
    "answer": "giving",
    "answerDetails": "Just giving things a finale vibe."
  },
  {
    "id": 3141,
    "question": "grupos",
    "questionDetails": "Me siento cómodo hablando en grupos pequeños.",
    "answer": "groups, bands, sets",
    "answerDetails": "I am perfectly comfortable speaking to small groups."
  },
  {
    "id": 3142,
    "question": "escuchen",
    "questionDetails": "Quiero que ustedes dos me escuchen.",
    "answer": "listen, heed",
    "answerDetails": "I want you two to listen to me."
  },
  {
    "id": 3143,
    "question": "mantiene",
    "questionDetails": "Mantiene alejada la oscuridad.",
    "answer": "keeps, maintains, holds",
    "answerDetails": "Keeps the dark away."
  },
  {
    "id": 3144,
    "question": "gesto",
    "questionDetails": "Maggie fue tocado por el gesto amable.",
    "answer": "gesture",
    "answerDetails": "Maggie was touched by the kind gesture."
  },
  {
    "id": 3145,
    "question": "inicio",
    "questionDetails": "El pasado jueves marcó el inicio oficial de la campaña electoral.",
    "answer": "start, beginning, onset",
    "answerDetails": "Last Thursday marked the official start of the electoral campaign."
  },
  {
    "id": 3146,
    "question": "absoluto",
    "questionDetails": "Los expertos clasificaron la campaña como un fracaso absoluto.",
    "answer": "unqualified",
    "answerDetails": "The pundits declared the campaign an unqualified disaster."
  },
  {
    "id": 3147,
    "question": "falla",
    "questionDetails": "Los sistemas de calefacción no suelen descomponerse por una falla grave sino por falta de Mantenimiento.",
    "answer": "fault, defect, flaw",
    "answerDetails": "Heating systems generally break down because of a lack of maintenance and not because of a major fault."
  },
  {
    "id": 3148,
    "question": "atento",
    "questionDetails": "Él era atento y reflexivo.",
    "answer": "thoughtful",
    "answerDetails": "He was attentive and thoughtful."
  },
  {
    "id": 3149,
    "question": "trataba",
    "questionDetails": "Creí que se trataba de otro juego.",
    "answer": "was, tried, treated",
    "answerDetails": "I thought it was for a stud game."
  },
  {
    "id": 3150,
    "question": "venden",
    "questionDetails": "Algunos asesores venden productos financieros.",
    "answer": "sell",
    "answerDetails": "Some planners also sell financial products."
  },
  {
    "id": 3151,
    "question": "experto",
    "questionDetails": "La opinión de un experto.",
    "answer": "expert, skilled",
    "answerDetails": "An expert opinion."
  },
  {
    "id": 3152,
    "question": "motor",
    "questionDetails": "Lo he intentado varias veces, pero el motor no arranca.",
    "answer": "engine",
    "answerDetails": "I’ve tried several times, but the engine won’t start."
  },
  {
    "id": 3153,
    "question": "humo",
    "questionDetails": "Más de un sueño está a punto de subir en el humo.",
    "answer": "smoke",
    "answerDetails": "More than one dream is about to go up in smoke."
  },
  {
    "id": 3154,
    "question": "hacíamos",
    "answer": "we did"
  },
  {
    "id": 3155,
    "question": "típico",
    "questionDetails": "El hoyo es típico del infierno.",
    "answer": "typical",
    "answerDetails": "The pit is typical of hell."
  },
  {
    "id": 3156,
    "question": "antiguo",
    "questionDetails": "Un antiguo amor un ex amor.",
    "answer": "old",
    "answerDetails": "An old flame."
  },
  {
    "id": 3157,
    "question": "patio",
    "answer": "patio"
  },
  {
    "id": 3158,
    "question": "inteligencia",
    "questionDetails": "El jefe de la inteligencia militar.",
    "answer": "intelligence",
    "answerDetails": "The chief of military intelligence."
  },
  {
    "id": 3159,
    "question": "rueda",
    "questionDetails": "El lanzamiento final de la rueda de la vida.",
    "answer": "wheel",
    "answerDetails": "The final release from the Wheel of life."
  },
  {
    "id": 3160,
    "question": "felicitaciones",
    "questionDetails": "Felicitaciones por el concurso.",
    "answer": "congratulations",
    "answerDetails": "Congratulations on winning the contest."
  },
  {
    "id": 3161,
    "question": "ayudarla",
    "questionDetails": "Quería ayudarla, pero simplemente no tenía tiempo.",
    "answer": "help her",
    "answerDetails": "I wanted to help her, but I just didn’t have time."
  },
  {
    "id": 3162,
    "question": "enteró",
    "questionDetails": "Aquí se enteró de quién era.",
    "answer": "learned",
    "answerDetails": "This is where he learned who he was."
  },
  {
    "id": 3163,
    "question": "soporto",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo lo soporto si él está allí.",
    "answer": "stand",
    "answerDetails": "I can only stand it when he’s there."
  },
  {
    "id": 3164,
    "question": "aguas",
    "questionDetails": "El barco entró en aguas extranjeras.",
    "answer": "waters",
    "answerDetails": "The ship entered foreign waters."
  },
  {
    "id": 3165,
    "question": "dato",
    "questionDetails": "Aprendí un dato interesante leyendo un artículo sobre ese actor. Resulta que habla 5 idiomas.",
    "answer": "tidbit",
    "answerDetails": "I learned an interesting tidbit reading an article about that actor. It turns out he speaks five languages."
  },
  {
    "id": 3166,
    "question": "cago",
    "questionDetails": "Me cago en eso.",
    "answer": "shit",
    "answerDetails": "I shit on that."
  },
  {
    "id": 3167,
    "question": "dejarla",
    "questionDetails": "Tuve que dejarla, para ganar dinero.",
    "answer": "leave",
    "answerDetails": "I had to leave it, to make money."
  },
  {
    "id": 3168,
    "question": "traición",
    "questionDetails": "Ese panfleto es alta traición.",
    "answer": "treason",
    "answerDetails": "That pamphlet is high treason."
  },
  {
    "id": 3169,
    "question": "sacarle",
    "questionDetails": "Para sacarle el veneno.",
    "answer": "get",
    "answerDetails": "To get the poison out."
  },
  {
    "id": 3170,
    "question": "navidad",
    "questionDetails": "Mis padres estaban encantados de que los podía visitar para la Navidad.",
    "answer": "christmas",
    "answerDetails": "My parents were delighted that I was able to visit for Christmas."
  },
  {
    "id": 3171,
    "question": "echarle",
    "questionDetails": "Quizá deberías echarle un vistazo.",
    "answer": "take, blame",
    "answerDetails": "Maybe you should take a look."
  },
  {
    "id": 3172,
    "question": "consejos",
    "questionDetails": "No hay consejos rápidos.",
    "answer": "tips, advice, councils",
    "answerDetails": "There are no quick tips."
  },
  {
    "id": 3173,
    "question": "preocuparte",
    "questionDetails": "Tan sólo no quería preocuparte.",
    "answer": "worry, fretting",
    "answerDetails": "I just didn’t want to worry you."
  },
  {
    "id": 3174,
    "question": "modos",
    "questionDetails": "Se llaman modos de cavidad.",
    "answer": "modes, ways",
    "answerDetails": "They are called cavity modes."
  },
  {
    "id": 3175,
    "question": "cuerpos",
    "questionDetails": "Hemos encontrado los cuerpos.",
    "answer": "bodies, corps",
    "answerDetails": "We found it by the bodies."
  },
  {
    "id": 3176,
    "question": "logrado",
    "answer": "authentic"
  },
  {
    "id": 3177,
    "question": "preocuparse",
    "questionDetails": "Comenzó a preocuparse por el nudo en la cuerda.",
    "answer": "worry",
    "answerDetails": "He began to worry at the knot in the cord."
  },
  {
    "id": 3178,
    "question": "sorpresas",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo que guardar algunas sorpresas.",
    "answer": "surprises",
    "answerDetails": "I gotta keep some surprises."
  },
  {
    "id": 3179,
    "question": "heridas",
    "questionDetails": "Aunque estas heridas no son nada.",
    "answer": "wounds, injuries, gunshot wounds",
    "answerDetails": "Yet these wounds are nothing."
  },
  {
    "id": 3180,
    "question": "echaron",
    "questionDetails": "Por eso la echaron de su antigua escuela.",
    "answer": "got kicked out",
    "answerDetails": "That’s why she got kicked out of her old school."
  },
  {
    "id": 3181,
    "question": "planeado",
    "questionDetails": "Nadie podía haberlo planeado.",
    "answer": "planned",
    "answerDetails": "Nobody could have planned this."
  },
  {
    "id": 3182,
    "question": "participar",
    "questionDetails": "La directora ejecutiva fue invitada pero decidió no participar.",
    "answer": "take part",
    "answerDetails": "The CEO was invited but decided not to take part."
  },
  {
    "id": 3183,
    "question": "título",
    "questionDetails": "El título del cuento es “Lobo Caprichoso”.",
    "answer": "title, heading",
    "answerDetails": "The title of the story is “Wayward Wolf.”."
  },
  {
    "id": 3184,
    "question": "baila",
    "answer": "Dance"
  },
  {
    "id": 3185,
    "question": "billetes",
    "answer": "paper money"
  },
  {
    "id": 3186,
    "question": "llamarme",
    "answer": "call me"
  },
  {
    "id": 3187,
    "question": "disfrutando",
    "questionDetails": "Demuestra que estás disfrutando la comida.",
    "answer": "enjoying, basking",
    "answerDetails": "It shows that you are enjoying a meal."
  },
  {
    "id": 3188,
    "question": "sonido",
    "questionDetails": "¿Qué es ese sonido?",
    "answer": "sound",
    "answerDetails": "What’s that sound?"
  },
  {
    "id": 3189,
    "question": "hacerla",
    "questionDetails": "Dijeron que podían hacerla de nuevo.",
    "answer": "make",
    "answerDetails": "They said they could make a new one."
  },
  {
    "id": 3190,
    "question": "únicos",
    "questionDetails": "Yo nunca he afirmado que mis poderes sean únicos.",
    "answer": "unique, only, sole",
    "answerDetails": "I never claimed that my powers were unique."
  },
  {
    "id": 3191,
    "question": "organizado",
    "questionDetails": "Bien organizado, lo hemos pasado bien.",
    "answer": "organized",
    "answerDetails": "Well organized, we had fun."
  },
  {
    "id": 3192,
    "question": "enterarse",
    "answer": "find out"
  },
  {
    "id": 3193,
    "question": "árbol",
    "questionDetails": "Árbol de levas.",
    "answer": "shaft, tree",
    "answerDetails": "Camshaft."
  },
  {
    "id": 3194,
    "question": "esconde",
    "questionDetails": "Cada hombre esconde una pena secreta.",
    "answer": "hides, conceals, lurking",
    "answerDetails": "Each man hides a secret pain."
  },
  {
    "id": 3195,
    "question": "regla",
    "questionDetails": "Tienes que seguir las reglas del juego.",
    "answer": "rule",
    "answerDetails": "You must follow the rules of the game."
  },
  {
    "id": 3196,
    "question": "subo",
    "questionDetails": "Yo subo siempre por las escaleras.",
    "answer": "climb, upload, raise",
    "answerDetails": "I climb the stairs every morning."
  },
  {
    "id": 3197,
    "question": "demos",
    "questionDetails": "Demos no puede hablar, el testigo tampoco.",
    "answer": "demos",
    "answerDetails": "Demos cannot speak, the witness cannot speak."
  },
  {
    "id": 3198,
    "question": "explica",
    "answer": "Explains"
  },
  {
    "id": 3199,
    "question": "puesta",
    "questionDetails": "… del período de armisticio y la puesta de los fundamentos para …",
    "answer": "laying",
    "answerDetails": "… of the armistice and the laying of the foundation for …"
  },
  {
    "id": 3200,
    "question": "raras",
    "questionDetails": "Ambos luchan con complejas cuerdas y raras melodías.",
    "answer": "rare, weird, strange",
    "answerDetails": "Both wrestle with complex chords and rare melodies."
  }
]